Séon O'Shannon

Developer | Manager



seon@eons.llc



+1 (775) 354-4343



Reno, NV



https://eons.llc

About me —

From biotechnology to de novo AI to custom clouds to business, my breadth of experience allows me to easily cross disciplines and move ideas from theory into practice. Diving deep into how systems work and learning what I can do to improve them is one of my great joys. It doesn't matter if I have to learn a new programming language, backdoor a broken server, design hardware, build new organisms, or change whole ecosystems, I'm up for any challenge and will take any opportunity to leave this world better than I found it.

Skills -

Leadership

C++

Python

WordPress (PHP, JS, CSS, HTML)

Cloud Architecture

Embedded Systems

Hardware & Electrical Engineering

Linux

Windows

Android

Version Control + CI/CD

Security

Experiment Design & Debugging

(*)[The skill scale represents confidence over perceived possible growth]

Experience

2021-now Solutions Architect

With AOE Greens, I designed and built fully integrated, custom IoT solutions. The CEO and I collaborated on hardware design, wired power, control, and actuation circuits for a hydroponic system. I then provided custom software and cloud infrastructure for controlling our

hardware through a secure web interface.

2020-now Founder & CEO

eons LLC

AOE Greens

My team and I grow new technologies. I manage vendor & customer relations, training, and onboarding. Our clients rely on our unique cloud infrastructure which I built, maintain, and secure. My work includes creating networking routes & iptables rules as well as building web backends, devops tools, and APIs in PHP, Python, &

C++.

2017-2021 Research Associate

Zeakal

I worked on a genetic engineering pipeline and managed other personnel, equipment, greenhouses, labs, and reagents. Using both Excel and Python, I wrote and mathematically verified software for automating the digestion of experimental data, enabling faster time-to-results across numerous studies. For collaboration with our global team, I built and hosted data servers for research results.

2015-2019 Lead Software Engineer

Brain2Bot

Using C++, Qt, & novel neuroscience I designed, developed, and deployed a software platform for building brains. I wrote drivers and wired together off-the-shelf hardware to create robot pets which responded to stimuli in real time, leaned from their experience, and had their own internal emotions & goals. I also deployed the same software with Unreal Engine targeting both Windows & Android.

Education

2013-2017

B.S. Biochemistry & Molecular Biology University of Nevada, Reno Thesis: "Overexpression of DGAT1 and Modified Cysteine Soy Oleosin Increases Oil Content in the Green Tissue of *Arabidopsis thaliana*", also earned a minor in mathematics.

GPA: 3.402

Achievements

2016 Secretary & Director

Reno Video Game Symphony

Designed & implemented a constitution for the Reno Video Game

Symphony and made the organization 501(c)(3) nonprofit.

2014 Eagle Scout

Boy Scouts of America

Eagle scout project was painting a map of the United States at Virginia

Palmer Elementary School.

Projects by Release Date

in progress Develop Biology

https://develop.bio

Open source, backwards compatible, recursive hypergraph with

reflection and a frontend as my own programming language.

2021 Eons Basic Build System

https://github.com/eons-dev/bin_ebbs

Extensible build system for any language and process, all in Python.

Web Infrastructure

https://web.infrastructure.tech/architecture/

Globally distributed Kubernetes cluster & auto-managed WordPress.

Latest

2020

Get the latest version of this resume at https://github.com/eons44/doc_resume References are available upon request (they will not be stored on the public repo).